Hey Chris.
やあ クリス
&gt;&gt; Hi Trinh.
&gt;&gt; やあ トリン
&gt;&gt; Over the past year that we've been working together on the careers team at
&gt;&gt; この 1 年間 私たちは
Udacity, you've developed so much, so many of our web apps, so
Udacity のキャリア チームで一緒に仕事をしてきましたね あなたは たくさんの ウェブ アプリを開発してきました
many of our data backend, and I was really surprised when I learned that
わが社のバックエンドと私 は
you've actually only been a software engineer for a year, and so
あなたが実際はソフトウェア エンジニアとしての経験が 1 年間あるだけだと聞いて とても驚きました
I'm just really curious to see how you got here?
どのようして ここまで成長できたのか教えてくださいますか?
&gt;&gt; Yeah, that's right.
&gt;&gt; そうですね
I've been a software engineer at Udacity for a year,
私は Udacity でソフトウェア エンジニア として 1 年間働いてきましたが
and my career I guess started a little bit more than ten years ago.
私のキャリアは 10 年以上前に始まりました
I was originally a admission counselor, and I got into tutoring and teaching.
私はもともと入試カウンセラーで , 個別指導と教育を行っていました
I even did a stint as an administrator working at a psychiatrist office
私は 精神科医のオフィスで管理者として働いたこともあったため
learning about medicine and health insurance.
薬や 健康保険に関する知識もありました
&gt;&gt; Well that's like a really diverse background.
&gt;&gt;いろいろな 背景をお持ちなんですね
How did you end up from a psychiatrist office to being a software engineer?
精神科医のオフィスt で働いていたのに どうやってソフトウェア エンジニアになったのですか?
&gt;&gt; So, it was definitely a long, winding road.
&gt;&gt; 間違いなく 遠い道のりでした
I think for
振り返ってみると
me, I first got curious about software engineering through teaching.
教えることから ソフトウェア エンジニアリングについて興味を持ちました
I made some courses at Udacity, in math and data analysis and product design.
Udacity において 数学 データ分析 製品設計のコースを作成しました
And along the way, I picked up coding skills, so
その中で '\r\n'
I learned a little bit about Python, I learned JavaScript.
Python について学び JavaScript も学びました
I learned how to think computationally,
私はコンピューターのように考える方法を学び
how to think kind of more like a computer scientist.
コンピューター サイエンティストのように 別の方法を考える方法を学びました
And I've just been learning ever since.
その時から学び続けています
And for me, I think, the biggest thing was trying to
私の場合 まず まず行ったことは
acquire all those skills and then convince people that I had enough skills
すべてのスキルを学び その後 私には何かを構築するのに十分なスキルがあり
to build something and to contribute to a larger organization.
大きな組織に貢献できるということを人々に納得させました
&gt;&gt; That's great that you brought that up.
&gt;&gt; 素晴らしい点を あげてくださいました
I speak with a lot of people about their career development and so
私は多くの人々と キャリア開発
many of them took the initiative,
について話しましたが 彼らも
like you, to learn on their own time, some while they're working full time.
あなたと同じようにどのようにフルタイムで働きながら 自分の時間で 学ぶように努力していました
But they still kind of face a barrier in that the it's hard for
しかし 彼らは ほかの人々に対して
them to convince people that, yes I am qualified and
私には能力があり
yes even though I don't have background in this job, I can still do it.
この仕事に関する背景はないが これはできると納得させることには壁を感じていました
How did you approach that problem?
どのように問題に立ち向かわれましたか?
&gt;&gt; Yeah, I mean it's certainly a hard one and I think it's easy to feel like
&gt;&gt; 確かに それは大変なことでした
you're an imposter, or you don't have enough skills.
詐欺師のように感じてしまうことや 十分なスキルがないと感じてしまうことはよくあることです
And I think the biggest thing you can do is one, practice, but also two,
私は一番にできることは 練習で
tell yourself that you are a software engineer.
二番目は 自分がソフトウェア エンジニアであることを言い聞かせることです
Talk about your projects.
プロジェクトについて話してください
Talk about them technically with other people.
ほかの人々と 技術的な話をしてください
That will build your confidence in your own abilities and
そうすることにより 自分自身の 能力と
your ability to communicate that you can do this work.
仕事を行う ことができるということを発信できるという自信を持つことができます
So I think for me, I know one of the things that I had to do was just kind of
私にとって 一番難しいことは
turn off that voice in my head that says you're not good enough.
脳裏に浮かぶ 自分には能力がないという考えと闘うことでした
Or you don't know enough things.
または 自分は十分なことを知らないという考えとも戦わなければなりません
Just turn off that imposter syndrome entirely and talk about what I can do,
インポスター症候群 を完全に捨て 自分ができることと
what I have done.
自分が達成したことについて考えることです
And that's what can really help you get an interview and
これが 面接に進み
succeed in those interviews.
面接で成功する鍵です
&gt;&gt; A lot of people when they're transitioning to a new career for
&gt;&gt; 多くの人が初めて 新しいキャリアに移行する際に
the first time, it's really hard for them to introduce themselves and
自分自身を紹介し
package everything that you just said about yourself into kind of a short
自分について語ったすべての事柄を
introduction to other people.
他の人への短い自己紹介のように伝えることを難しく感じています
So do you have any strategies on how people can approach talking
他の人に キャリアの変更を
to other people about their career change?
伝えるための戦略を 何かお持ちですか?
&gt;&gt; Yeah I think one of the best things that you can do is to use
&gt;&gt; できることの一つの方法は'\r\n'
an elevator pitch.
簡潔に自分自身を説明することです